Mothering Sunday is a romance, drama film directed by Eva Husson.
On a warm spring day in 1924, house maid and foundling Jane
Fairchild finds herself alone on Mother's Day.
Her employers, Mr.
Niven, are out and she has the rare chance to spend
quality time with her secret lover.
Paul is the boy from the manor house nearby, Jane's long-term love despite the fact that he's engaged to
be married to another woman, a childhood friend and daughter of his parents' friends.
But events that neither can foresee will change
the course of Jane's life forever.
Jane Fairchild, played by Odessa Young.
Paul Sheringham, played by Josh O'Connor.
Donald, played by Ṣọpẹ́ Dìrísù.
Milly, played by Patsy Ferran.
Emma Hobday, played by Emma D'Arcy.
Jane (Older), played by Glenda Jackson.
Mothering Sunday is a 2021 British period romantic drama film directed by Eva Husson, from a
screenplay by Alice Birch, based on Graham Swift's novel of the same name.
The film follows the life of Jane Fairchild, played by Odessa Young, particularly during a Mothering Sunday
in the wake of World War I which she spends with her wealthy lover, played by Josh O'Connor.
Ṣọpẹ́ Dìrísù, Olivia Colman, and Colin Firth are also among the cast.
The film also marks the first appearance of Glenda Jackson in a theatrical release in over 30 years, having
last appeared in King of the Wind (1990), as well as the penultimate film role of her lifetime.
Mothering Sunday had its world premiere at the
Cannes Film Festival on 9 July 2021.
It received positive reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
england, post world war i, maid, mother's day.
The tone is emotional.